Mathieu Bruguier

Full Stack Developer

Summary

Full Stack developer with more than 5 years of industry experience. Great team-worker, adaptable leader and humble learner. Always willing to embrace new challenges. Expert in *Javascript* frameworks such as **Node.js** and **Angular 5**, as well as object-oriented languages like **C#**, **Java** and **C++**. Highly interested in UX/UI. Loves making video games during free time.

Work experience

Full Stack Developer 2016 - 2018

SeeTickets US - Los Angeles, California

- Built ticket kiosk iPad application using Ionic Framework and Angular 5, currently in use all over the United States.
- Helped in-progress microservice architecture migration (from .NET monolith), primarily built on **Node.js**, **Express**, **Angular 5** and using the **Serverless** framework as well as the whole **AWS** deployment stack (**CodePipeline**, **Cloudformation**, **Lambda**).
- Established new thorough and efficient development best practices such as continuous integration, code style guides (Linting), code review/testing, etc..
- Daily bug management and feature additions on lame-duck production system (monolithic program built using VB.net, WAF framework, SQL Server, Javascript, and C#).

.Net/Full Stack Developer

2014 - 2016

Azzana Consulting - Paris, France

- Developed desktop solutions as well as fully featured websites used by the largest banks in France.
- Created websites from scratch using ASP.Net/HTML/CSS/Javascript following Google's Material Design.

.Net Developer 2012 - 2013

Seayard - Marseille, France

- Created a software capable of tracking every single machine on site and allowing the workers to trigger an alarm in case of emergency.

Education

Master's degree 2010 - 2015

EPITECH - European Institute of Technology

GPA - 3.48

One of the most prestigious computer science schools in France.

As part of its teaching pedagogy, Epitech encourages skilled students to provide assistance to junior students. I came to them, offering to create a **Game Development Lab**, and I was in charge of about twenty students passionate about video games.

Computer Science 2013 - 2014

California State University-Long Beach

Two semesters abroad, to discover the American culture and fall in love with the Californian way of life. Classes: Computer Science, Algorithms, Game Theory